Guide to the George Jarvis Brush Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George Jarvis Brush family papers
1834-1960
1834-1939
MS 108
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(10 boxes, 1 folio)
Correspondence, writings, lectures, notes, printed material, and other papers, principally of George Jarvis Brush (1831-1912), mineralogist, geologist, and educator; and of his son-in-law, Louis Valentine Pirsson (1860-1919), also a geologist. There are also papers of Brush's wife, Harriet Silliman Trumbull Brush and of other family members. A good deal of the papers are scientific in nature, with some relating to the early history of the Yale Sheffield Scientific School. Important correspondents include William H. Brewer, Charles F. Chandler, Josiah P. Cooke, Whitman Cross, James Dwight Dana, Timothy Dwight, Charles W. Eliot, Joseph Henry, Lyman Trumbull, Joseph Wharton, and Josiah Dwight Whitney.
Brush, George Jarvis, 1831-1912
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Louis V. Pirsson, 1943-1950.
Existence and Location of Copies
Scrapbooks of Sarah Jarvis Brush McLaughlin and Edward Tompkins McLaughlin are available on microfilm (170 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM 143.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence. II. Special Files.
Scope and Contents
The Brush Family Papers consist primarily of the correspondence of mineralogist, geologist, and educator, George Jarvis Brush and that of his son-in-law, also a geologist, Louis Valentine Pirsson. The collection will be of interest to those interested in the study of mineralogy in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. There are also materials relating to scientific education, especially at Yale's Sheffield Scientific School, and to the position of science in America. In addition, there are materials relating to the Civil War and the political turmoil of that period, as well as personal and family papers relating to the Brush, Pirsson, and James Dwight Dana families.
The collection is divided into two series, "Correspondence" and "Special Files." The Correspondence series consists of the correspondence of the following six individuals: George Jarvis Brush, Harriet Silliman (Trumbull) Brush, Sarah Jarvis (Brush) McLaughlin, Eliza Trumbull (Brush) Pirsson, Louis Valentine Pirsson, and Jane Lathrop Trumbull.
The largest group of correspondence is that of George Jarvis Brush. Among the correspondents found in this section are many prominent European and American scientists and American educators including: William Henry Brewer (25 items), Charles Frederick Chandler (22 items), Josiah P. Cooke, Jr. (59 items), James Dwight Dana (39 items), Charles W. Eliot (49 items), Frederick Augustus Genth (42 items), Joseph Henry (15 items), Clarence King (11 items), Franz von Kobell (8 items), William Theodore Roepper (59 items), John Lawrence Smith (60 items), Joseph Wharton (77 items), and Josiah Dwight Whitney (43 items). Most of the correspondence in this section concerns the identification, exchange, and purchase of mineral specimens. There is, however, correspondence, notably with Timothy Dwight, on the administration of the Sheffield Scientific School and Yale University. In addition, there are letters from Thomas Egleston and Charles W. Eliot about scientific education in America.
The correspondence of Louis Valentine Pirsson, Brush's son-in-law, is also largely scientific, much of it relating to Pirsson's work on the geology of Montana and other western states. Among the important correspondents are Whitman Cross (57 items), Henry Stephens Washington (19 items), and Walter Harvey Weed (64 items).
The correspondence of Brush's wife, Harriet Silliman (Trumbull) Brush, includes 117 letters from Henrietta Francis Dana, wife of James Dwight Dana, and 45 letters from Elizabeth Sarah Grimes, wife of Iowa governor, James W. Grimes. There are also 13 letters from Senator Lyman Trumbull of Illinois. A recurrent topic in Mrs. Brush's correspondence is the Civil War and the political troubles of this period.
This series also includes the correspondence of Jane Lathrop Trumbull (sister of Mrs. Brush), Eliza Trumbull (Brush) Pirsson, Sarah Jarvis (Brush) McLaughlin, and Jane Lathrop Trumbull. Of special interest are Brush's lectures and notes on geology and L.V. Pirsson's diary of his trip to the International Geological Conference held in 1897 in St. Petersburg, Russia. The diary also includes Pirsson's geological observations made on several excursions in Norway and Russia. In addition, there is a manuscript by Pirsson and W.H. Weed on the geology of the Highwood Mountains of Montana and a manuscript of an unpublished textbook on geology by Pirsson. There are also a few photographs of the two men, some biographical materials, and a folder of genealogical materials on the Brush and Trumbull families.
Biographical / Historical
George Jarvis Brush, mineralogist and head of Yale's Sheffield Scientific School, was born on December 15, 1831, the son of Jarvis and Sarah Brush, in Brooklyn, New York. In 1835, the Brush family moved to Danbury, Connecticut, where they resided for six years, only to return to Brooklyn in 1841.
When Brush was fifteen, he attended a private school in West Cornwall, Connecticut headed by Theodore S. Gold. Although he only attended the school for six months, Gold aroused his interest in natural science. After leaving school, Brush was employed by a New York mercantile house where he worked for two years until a serious illness in 1848 prompted him to leave business and consider farming for a career. In order to prepare himself for this new career, Brush entered Yale College in 1848 enrolling in the School of Applied Chemistry. He attended lectures in agricultural and practical chemistry given by John Pitkin Norton and Benjamin Silliman, Jr. Two years later he became an assistant to Benjamin Silliman, Jr., who was teaching in the medical department of Louisville University, a position Brush held until 1852. As a result of his prolonged absence from New Haven, Brush was required to take special examinations. Nevertheless he graduated with the first class of the new Yale Scientific School, receiving a Ph.D. in 1852. Later, under Brush's guidance and leadership, this department became the Sheffield Scientific School.
After graduation, Brush spent a year (1852-1853) at the University of Virginia as an assistant in chemistry. It was here that Brush became associated with the chemist and mineralogist, John Lawrence Smith. Together they worked on a series of mineralogical experiments, the results of which were published in the American Journal of Science. Brush spent the summer of 1853 as an assistant in charge of the department of mineralogy at the Crystal Palace of the International Exposition in New York, but in the fall he sailed for Germany where he continued his studies under Liebig, von Kobell, and Pettenkoffer, and also studied at the mining school at Freiberg, Saxony.
In 1855, Brush was appointed professor of metallurgy at the Sheffield Scientific School. To prepare himself for this position, he studied during the year of 1856 at the Royal School of Mines in London and visited mines and smelting works in Great Britain and on the continent. The following year he assumed his duties at Yale. In 1864 his position was expanded to include mineralogy and by 1871 Brush was devoting himself exclusively to mineralogy, his major field of interest.
Brush's career as a scientist was closely related to the development of the Sheffield Scientific School, of which he became president in 1872. In fact, much of his time was devoted to the administration of the school thus forcing him to gradually abandon his teaching duties. By the end of the 1870's, he had given up laboratory instruction; by 1884, lectures as well. He continued as the director of the Sheffield Scientific School until 1898. Thereafter, he served variously as secretary, treasurer and president of the Board of Trustees of the school until his death on February 6, 1912.
Although Brush's scientific work was ultimately restricted by his administrative duties, he nevertheless made several important contributions to the study of mineralogy. His studies with J. Lawrence Smith have already been mentioned. His Manual of Determinative Mineralogy, published in 1874, was a clear and concise summary of blowpipe methods and principles and included determinative tables adapted from those of von Kobell. The book went through several editions. In addition, Brush left to the Sheffield Scientific School an extremely complete and well-catalogued collection of mineral specimens numbering some 15,000 items.
Brush married Harriet Silliman Trumbull in 1864. They had three daughters: Sarah Jarvis, Bertha De Forest, and Eliza Trumbull. His wife died in 1910, and Brush two years later.
LOUIS VALENTINE PIRSSON
Louis Valentine Pirsson, geologist and Yale professor, was born November 3, 1860 to Francis Morris and Louisa (Butt) Pirsson. He saw little of his natural parents for his mother died when he was four and his father was frequently away. At the age of nine, Pirsson became the ward of Thomas Lord of New York, who placed him with the family of the Reverend William J. Blain on a farm near Amsterdam, New York. Young Pirsson received his early education from Blain and displayed an interest in natural history. When he was sixteen, he went to the Amenia Academy in Dutchess County, New York, and in 1879 he entered the Sheffield Scientific School from which he graduated with honors in 1882.
In 1889, through the help of George Jarvis Brush, Pirsson became a field assistant of the United States Geological Survey party under Arnold Hague then studying Yellowstone Park. This experience stimulated his interest in igneous geology, a subject he further studied in Heidelberg and in Paris.
In 1892 Brush invited Pirsson to teach mineralogy and lithology at Yale and, the following year, he gave the first graduate course in petrology at Yale. Pirsson became an assistant professor in 1894 and professor of physical geology in 1897. In addition, he held many administrative positions in the Sheffield Scientific School, was an associate editor of the American Journal of Science from 1899 until his death in 1919, and was the author of many works on geology, including Rocks and Rock Minerals (1908) and Textbook of Geology (1915).
Pirsson married Brush's oldest daughter, Eliza Trumbull Brush, in 1902.
Conditions Governing Access
The scrapbooks in this collection have been microfilmed (HM 143). Patrons must use microfilm instead of originals.
Families; Geology; Mineralogy; Science; Europe -- Description and travel; Europe; New York (State); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; West (U.S.); Diaries; Educators; Geologists; Mineralogists; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887; Bauerman, Hilary, 1834-1909; Blake, Eli Whitney, 1836-1895; Blanford, W. T. (William Thomas), 1832-1905; Brewer, William Henry, 1828-1910; Brush, George Jarvis, 1831-1912; Chandler, Charles Frederick, 1836-1925; Chittenden, R. H. (Russell Henry), 1856-1943; Cooke, Josiah P., Jr. (Josiah Parsons), 1827-1894; Cross, Whitman, 1854-1949; Dana, Henrietta Frances Silliman, 1823-1907; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895; Des Cloizeaux, A. (Alfred), 1817-1897; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; Egleston, Thomas, 1832-1900; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926; Eschweiler, Charles F.; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867; Fisher, Robert A., b.ca. 1833; Genth, Frederich August Ludwig Karl Wilheim, 1820-1893; Gibbs, Wolcott, 1822-1908; Gilman, Daniel C. (Daniel Coit), 1831-1908; Gold, Theodore S. (Theodore Sedgwick), 1818-1906; Grimes, Elizabeth Sarah Nealley; Hagemann, Gustav, 1853-; Hague, James D. (James Duncan), 1836-1908; Hawes, George W. (George Wesson), 1848-1882; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878; Hitchcock, Edward, 1828-1911; Jeffries, William W.; King, Clarence, 1842-1901; Kobell, Franz von, 1803-1882; Krantz, Jean Baptiste Sʹebastien, b. 1817; Longfellow, Alice M. (Alice Mary), 1850-1928; Lounsbury, Thomas R., 1838-1915; Marsh, Othniel Charles, 1831-1899; Moore, George Henry, 1823-1892; Pirsson, Louis V. (Louis Valentine), 1860-1919; Ramsay, A. C. (Andrew Crombie), 1814-1891; Rockwell, Alfred Perkins, 1834-1903; Roepper, W. Th. (William Theodore); Rood, Ogden N. (Ogden Nicholas), 1831-1902; Root, Oren, 1838-1885; Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885; Smith, J. Lawrence (John Lawrence), 1818-1883; Smyth, Warington W. (Warington Wilkinson), 1817-1890; Storer, Frank H. (Frank Humphreys), 1832-1914; Taylor, William J, 1833-1864; Teall, J. J. H. (Jethro Justinian Harms), 1849-1924; Torrey, John, 1796-1873; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1810-1883; Trumbull, Julia Maria Jayne, 1823-1868; Trumbull, Lyman, 1813-1896; Walker, Francis Amasa, 1840-1897; Washington, Henry S. (Henry Stephens), 1867-1934; Weed, Walter Harvey, 1862-1944; Weld, Mason Cogswell, 1829-1887; Wharton, Joseph, 1826-1909; Whitney, J. D. (Josiah Dwight), 1819-1896; Whitney, William Dwight, 1827-1894; Williams, George Huntington, 1856-1894; Brush family; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Sheffield Scientific School
- Correspondence, 1850-1907, 1909-1912, 1914, 1916-1920, 1924, 1932, 1939, 1960, undated; Series I; 3' (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The CORRESPONDENCE series is divided into two subsections: "General Correspondence" and "Correspondence of Others." "General Correspondence" is divided into six subgroups as follows: George Jarvis Brush, Harriet Silliman (Trumbull) Brush, Sarah Jarvis (Brush) McLaughlin, Eliza Trumbull (Brush) Pirsson, Louis Valentine Pirsson, and Jane Lathrop Trumbull.
  The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter or by the name of the person to whom the letter is addressed. Letters are arranged chronologically within each folder.
  "Correspondence of Others" is arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter.
  A folder containing unidentified material is filed at the end of the series.
  The number of items is contained in parentheses.
  - George Jarvis Brush
    - A (2), 1871-1872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agassiz, Alexander, (1835-1910) (1), 1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Agassiz, Jean Louis Rodolphe, (1807-1873) (1) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Allen, Oscar Dana (5), 1867-1869 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ames, Horatio (5), 1862, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ames, James Tyler (3), 1862-1863 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anderberg, [Wilhelm?] (9), 1861-1864, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Angell, James Burrill (2), 1872, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ashburner, William (6), 1862-1863, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - B (18), 1853, 1854, 1858, 1860, 1863-1865, 1867, 1868, 1874, 1881, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bailey, Loring Woart (1), 1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bailey, Stratford C.H. (2), 1863-1864 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Baird, Spencer F. (3), 1862, 1864, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter (2), 1868, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bauerman, Hilary (17), 1871, 1876, 1877, 1881, 1887, 1888, 1890-1894, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bechi, Emilio (3), 1886, 1891, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Becker and Sons (6), 1862, 1863, 1865, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bement, Clarence S. (1), 1877 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blake, Eli Whitney, Jr. (4), 1861, 1862, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Blake, Helen M. (Rood) (7), 1854, 1860, 1862 1864 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Blake, William P., 1858, 1859, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Blanford, Wm. Thomas (30), 1855-1857, 1860, 1862, 1865, 1868, 1881, 1887, 1888-1889 1893, 1895-1898, 1900-1902 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bondi, Dr. M. (15), 1856-1861 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bradley, Chares William (1), 1862 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bradley, Frank Howe (4), 1866, 1868, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Breithaup, J.F. August (3), 1860, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Brewer, William Henry (25), 1850, 1853, 1854, 1857, 1858, 1860, 1861, 1864, 1875, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Brooks, Thomas Benton (1), 1865 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Buckingham, William Alfred (1), 1865 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bushnell, Horace (1), 1873 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - C (28), 1859, 1861, 1863-1868, 1870, 1875, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Cassin, John (1), 1868 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Chandler, Charles Frederick (22), 1859-1862, 1864-1866, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chittenden, Russell H. (2), 1882, 1911, 1859-1865 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Clay, Joseph A. (8), 1859-1865 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Collier, Maurice Dwight (1), 1868 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Collier, Peter (8), 1866, 1868-1869 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Cook, George Hammell (4), 1860, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Cooke, Josiah P., Jr. (56), 1859-1863, 1865-1870, 1873-1874, 1877-1878, 1886, 1890, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Coxe, Eckley B. (1), 1881 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - D (17), 1855, 1863, 1866, 1868, 1871-1875, 1882, 1908, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - d'Aligny, Henry F. Quarré, 1862, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Dana, Edward S. (1), 1906 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      General note
      See also: box 7, folder 218
    - Dana, Henrietta F. (Silliman) (1), 1860 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Dana, James Dwight (39), 1852-1856, 1863-1864, 1874, 1878, 1881, 1885, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Delesse, Achille Ernest Oscar J. (2), 1861, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Des Cloizeau, Alfred L.O.L. (7), 1862, 1863, 1872-1873, 1875, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Drown, Thomas M. (1), 1863 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - DuBois, Augustus Jay (1), 1885 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Dwight, Timothy (1828-1916) (18), 1862-1864, 1870, 1885-1886, 1888, 1890-1891, 1896-1899, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - E (4), 1854, 1860, 1864, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Eichwald, Julius (6), 1861-1862, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Eisenhardt, August von (3), 1892, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Elderhorst, William (3), 1858, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Egleston, Thomas (12), 1861-1864, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Eliot, Charles William (50), 1860-1863, 1865, 1867-1869, 1871-1872, 1875, 1877, 1882-1883, 1886-1889, 1891, 1893, 1896-1897, 1899, 1901-1902, 1912, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Emerson, George H. (2), 1864 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Emmons, Samuel Franklin (1), 1874 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Eschweiler, Charles F. (3), 1861, 1863, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - F (1), 1874 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Farnum, William W. (4), 1899-1900 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Fisher, Davenport (12), 1854-1855, 1865, 1867, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Fisher, George Park (4), 1885 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Fisher, Robert A. (14), 1860, 1862-1864, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Forbes, David (12), 1856-1857, 1860, 1863-1864, 1866, 1875, 1886, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Forchhammer, Johann G. (2), 1859, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - G (8), 1850, 1857, 1862, 1864, 1865, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Gaupillar, E. (2), 1860, 1897[?] (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Geikie, Sir Archibald (2), 1893, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Geinitz, Hans Bruno (2), 1860, 1871 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Genth Frederick Augustus (42), 1857, 1859-1863, 1865, 1868, 1870, 1875, 1877-1878 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Gerland, W. (1), 1854 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Geyer, T. (1), 1856 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Gibbs, George (1), 1864 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Gibbs, Oliver Wolcott (32), 1858, 1861-1863, 1866-1868, 1871, 1875-1876, 1882, 1884, 1888, 1890, 1895, 1903, 1905, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Gillespie, William Mitchell (1), 1859 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Gilman, Daniel Colt (12), 1872-1875, 1882, 1889, 1898, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Gold, Theodore S. (6), 1857, 1863-1864, 1869, 1902, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Goodale, George Lincoln (1), 1882 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Goodyear, Watson Andrews (5), 1863-1864, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Gould, Benjamin A., 1824-1896 (3), 1890 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Groth, Paul Heinrich (3), 1881, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - H (28), 1853-1856, 1859, 1861 1866, 1868, 1872, 1898, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Hagemann, Gustav (10), 1865-1866 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Hague, Arnold (1), 1875 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Hague, James Duncan (15), 1862-1864, 1866, 1869, 1877, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Hall, James, 1811-1898 (3), 1853 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Hammond, John Hays (2), 1894, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Hartley, Edward (1), 1864 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Hawes, George Wesson (11), 1877, 1879, 1880 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Henry, Joseph (15), 1860-1864, 1866, 1868 1869 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Herrmann, Charles W. A. (4), 1861, 1864, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Hilgard, Eugene W. (3), 1857, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Hilgard, Julius E. (4), 1861, 1863, 1871, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Hill, Nathaniel Peter (3), 1862-1863, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Hitchcobk, Edward (10), 1858, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Hopkins, Mark (1), 1868 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Hungerford, Edward (5), 1857, 1861, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Hugershoff, W. (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Hunt, Thomas Sterry (18), 1856-1861, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - J (4), 1866, 1867, 1868, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Jeffries, William W. (17), 1857, 1860-1864, 1866, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Jewett, Ezekiel (7), 1859, 1861, 1863-1864 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Johnson, Samuel W. (5), 1853-1854 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Johnston, John (4), 1854, 1861, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Joy, Charles Arad (16), 1858, 1861-1864, 1867, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - K (15), 1858-1859, 1861-1864, 1867-1868, 1881, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Kengott, Gustav Adolf (18), 1855-1857, 1860-1864, 1869, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Kimball, James Putnam (10), 1859, 1861-1863 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - King, Clarence (11), 1863, 1867, 1869, 1874-1875, 1878-1879, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Kobell, Franz von (8), 1854-1855, 1858-1859, 1863, 1864, 1867, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Koenig, George Augustus (1), 1870 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Krantz, Jean Baptiste S. (11), 1857, 1859-1863, 1868, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Kühne, Willy (2), 1886 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - L (7), 1859-1860, 1863-1864, 1867, 1882, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Lea, Isaac (1), 1868 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - LeConte, John Lawrence (5), 1867-1868 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Lesley, J. Peter (4), 1861, 1865-1866 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Lockyer, Sir Joseph Norman (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Lounsbury, Thomas R. (11), 1885, 1890-1892, 1895, 1898, 1902, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - M (22), 1856, 1859, 1862-1869, 1871, 1876, 1902, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Marsh, Othniel C. (2), 1864, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Martinez, Marcial (1), 1883 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Matthiessen, Frederick W. (5), 1861, 1863-1864, 1866, 1867-1868 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Maynard, George W. (4), 1867-1868 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Meek, Fielding Bradford (1), 1869 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Meneghini, Giuseppe (1), 1860 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Miers, Sir Henry Alexander (1), 1900 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Moore, George Henry (10), 1862-1864, 1866, 1869, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Moore, Gideon E. (1), 1861 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Muspratt, Edmund K. (7), 1858, 1876, 1894-1895, 1896, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Muspratt, Max (1), 1894 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - N (4), 1858, 1864, 1875, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Nason, Henry Bradford (3), 1866, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Naumann, Karl Friedrich (1), 1855 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Newberry, John Strong (6), 1861-1862, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Nicholskii, L. (1), 1876 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Nordhoff, Charles (1), 1899 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Nye, James Warren (1), 1866 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Ordway, John Morse (1), 1861 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Orton, James (1), 1868 (Box 3, Folder 94)